<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>LinkedPool</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/linkedpool/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/linkedpool/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-idea&#34;&gt;The Idea&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon starting at Columbia University, introductory lectures often ended with instructors sharing their LinkedIn profiles, inviting students to connect. While connecting with lecturers was great, I found myself more interested in networking with my peers. To address this, I thought of a web application where users could scan a QR code that links to a site displaying the LinkedIn names and profile pictures of others who had scanned the same code. The concept included a feature to connect directly via a simple button next to each name.
From the start, I knew the application needed to be as seamless as possible to have any chance of being used. With this intuition in mind, I coined the name LinkedPool, sought a logo from DALL-E, and began the development process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schokoban: Using Monte Carlo Tree Search for Solving Sokoban</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/schokoban/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/schokoban/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Sokoban Puzzle&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/level_1.png&#34; title=&#34;Sokoban Puzzle&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Level 1 from the original Sokoban game&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s thesis, under the supervision of &lt;a href=&#34;https://people.math.ethz.ch/~jopeters/&#34;&gt;Professor Dr. Peters&lt;/a&gt;, I explored the application of Monte Carlo Tree Search to the puzzle game Sokoban. Sokoban challenges players to push boxes onto designated targets within a warehouse. Even though the rules of Sokoban are simple, they still allow for complex and engaging puzzles. The research presents a novel approach to manage redundant state representations within the Monte Carlo Search Tree, significantly enhancing the algorithm’s ability to solve problems. Below is a preview of the comparative results between the baseline and the improved algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Paul</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pages/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pages/about/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently pursuing my Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Computer Science at Columbia University, New York, following my undergraduate studies in Mathematics at ETH Zürich.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am deeply curious and constantly seeking to expand my knowledge across various topics in Statistics and Computer Science. I advocate for first principles thinking, striving to thoroughly understand the intricacies of each subject I explore. Conversation is a vital tool for this kind of learning, and I’m always open to engaging discussions. Please feel free to connect with me on LinkedIn — hopefully we can grab a coffee.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
